Reproductive Rights National Network Records, 1970-1985
Sophia Smith Collection
Reproductive Rights National Network records
1970-1985
Reproductive Rights National Network
MS 586 UUID:985425e0-4c9b-430a-b740-73d40b7435f6
18 boxes (8.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Reproductive rights advocacy group. Records contain materials on political actions and activities; abortion legislation; affiliate organizations; women's clinics across the U.S.; and subject files. Member organization and subject files comprise the bulk of the records. In addition there are significant materials on allied organizations. Subject files include abortion; sterilization; other women's health issues; and the anti-abortion movement.
The Reproductive Rights National Network (R2N2) began as a "non-organization" brought together informally late in 1977 by the Chicago-based New American Movement. It was a coalition of local grassroots organizations formed to counter right-wing anti-abortion movement's lobbying, activism, and propaganda and to provide visibility for a reproductive rights perspective in the women's and health movements. In February 1979, the coalition decided to form a centralizing national organization to support local efforts and coordinate strategy. More than 80 autonomous member groups eventually joined the Network, committing to its "principles of unity."
R2N2's goal was to bring women together from diverse groups that had not worked successfully together before. While early efforts focused on abortion access and sterilization abuse, over time the group came to define its work more broadly including work against racism and all forms of oppression, infant mortality, and violence; and advocacy for quality health care, child care, sufficient income, and lesbian and disability rights. R2N2's work included publishing the Reproductive Rights Newsletter, organizing national meetings, and promoting direct action on a wide range of issues. Periodic national conferences served as the "main political and organizational decision-making body" for the Network.
"Chronic decline in the movement" during the politically conservative Reagan Administration challenged the Network's ability to sustain its funding and membership which in turn made tensions over racism and heterosexism within R2N2 particularly difficult to address. In the face of burnout and dwindling participation, R2N2 organized a national conference in November 1984, "Beyond Rhetoric: The Realities of Multi-Racial Organizing," with "serious doubts about survival of the network." Women of color at the conference challenged R2N2's failure to address internal racism as a priority issue and ultimately decided to leave the Network to form a separate women of color group. According to a report of the conference, "total communication breakdown" and pressure from women of color, prompted white women at the conference to commit to come together early in 1985 to discuss the conference and their roles and responsibilities in addressing racism within themselves and their local groups. They ultimately decided they did not want to continue as a Network of white women.
The records include materials pertaining to R2N2 political actions and activities; files on affiliate organizations and women's clinics across the U.S.; information about abortion legislation; and subject files concerning many related topics, including the anti-abortion movement. Member organization and subject files comprise the bulk of the records. In addition to materials about R2N2, the records contain significant materials about allied organizations including the Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA), Mobilization for Survival (MfS), Committee to Defend Reproductive Rights (CDRR), and Women Organized for Reproductive Choice (WORC). Subject files focus heavily on women's health issues, defined widely, but emphasizing abortion and sterilization in particular. The subject files also document the rise of the Moral Majority/New Right and the activities and policies of the Reagan administration.
This collection is organized into five series:
SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION, 1978-84, n.d.
SERIES II. MEMBER ORGANIZATIONS, 1973-85, n.d.
SERIES III. EVENTS, 1979-83, n.d.
SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES, 1970-85, n.d.
SERIES V. ARTIFACTS
OVERSIZE MATERIALS
The Records are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
Katherine Acey donated the Records of the Reproductive Rights National Network (R2N2) to the Sophia Smith Collection in 2007. Additional records are housed at the Wisconsin Social History Archives, the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library at Duke University, and in Archives and Special Collections at Northeastern University.
Abortion -- Political aspects -- United States -- History -- Sources; Abortion -- Law and legislation -- United States -- History -- Sources; Pro-choice movement -- United States -- History -- Sources; Involuntary sterilization--Law and legislation-- United States; Feminists -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Latina women -- Health and hygiene -- United States; Reproductive health -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Reproductive rights -- United States -- History -- Sources; Birth control -- Law and legislation -- United States -- History -- Sources; Sterilization (birth control) -- History -- Sources; Race awareness -- United States; Women's health services -- United States -- History -- Sources; Reproductive Rights National Network; Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse
Associated material can be found in the Sophia Smith Collection in Saralee Hamilton Papers and in the Alliance Against Women's Oppression Records, and in oral histories with Marlene Fried and Meredith Tax that are part of the Voices of Feminism Oral History Project.
- SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION 91978-84, undated), .75 linear ft.
  This series provides an overview of activities at Reproductive Rights National Network's headquarters and its organizational structure. The series includes correspondence, information related to donations, files on issues addressed by the national office in independent actions, and publications. Drafts of brochures are included. Materials on R2N2's work in collaboration with its member organization, CARASA, can be found in SERIES II. See also SERIES VI. ARTIFACTS.
- SERIES II. MEMBER ORGANIZATIONS 1973-85, undated, 3 linear ft.
  This series includes information related to member organizations of R2N2. It includes correspondence with the R2N2 national office, news clippings, pamphlets, newsletters, other publications, and files on events organized by R2N2 member organizations. The series is arranged alphabetically by organization name.
  Correspondence about men's involvement in reproductive rights organizations in the CARASA files, materials revealing tensions between pacifist and feminist organizers in the Mobilization for Survival files, and an exchange about heterosexism and homophobia in R2N2 in the Portland Women's Health Center file are of particular interest.
- SERIES III. EVENTS 1979-83, undated, .5 linear ft.
  This series consists of correspondence; brochures; flyers; news clippings; notes; press releases and statements; and a few photographs related to events organized, sponsored, or endorsed by R2N2.
- SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION
  - General and history, 1977-83, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Conferences
    - Mar 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Nov 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Nov 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1980-81 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
      - 1982-84, undated (Box 1A, Folder 1-4)
    - Form letter to organizations Jan 1982 (Box 1A, Folder 5)
    - "Individuals and groups no longer existing or out of Network" 1980-81 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
  - Donations 1980-81 (Box 1A, Folder 7)
  - Issues
    - Abortion 1978-83, undated (Box 1A, Folder 8)
    - Affirmative action 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 9)
    - Child care 1980-82, undated (Box 1A, Folder 10)
    - Depo-Provera 1982 (Box 1A, Folder 11)
    - The Family: R2N2 packets 1981-84, undated (Box 1A, Folder 12)
    - Family Protection Act: agendas, drafts, and notes 1981-82 (Box 1A, Folder 13)
    - Human Life Amendment brochure drafts 1981, undated (Box 1A, Folder 14)
    - Lesbian rights 1982, undated (Box 1A, Folder 15)
    - Population control bill 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 16)
    - Sterilization 1980-82, undated (Box 1A, Folder 17-18)
  - Population control slideshow circa 1981 (Box 1A, Folder 19)
  - Publications, miscellaneous 1984 (Box 1A, Folder 20)
  - Reproductive rights fact sheets undated (Box 1A, Folder 21)
  - Reproductive Rights Newsletter (including early issues published by NAM)
    - 1978-81 (Box 1A, Folder 22-24)
    - 1982-83 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - R2N2 News 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Taking Control: The Magazine of the Reproductive Rights National Network, Vol. 1, No. 1, spr 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Women's Liberation Zap Action Brigade: R2N2 press statement and background 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- SERIES II. MEMBER ORGANIZATIONS
  - Abortion by Choice (Calgary, Alberta, Canada) 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Alliance for Reproductive Rights/Cincinnati (ARRC, formerly Abortion Rights Committee) 1980-84, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Abortion Rights Movement (ARM) 1979-80, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Action Committee for Abortion Rights (ACAR) 1982-84, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Alliance Against Women's Oppression (AAWO)
    - General 1981-84 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Abortion Task Force paper 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Conflict with CDRR 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) 1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Americans for Choice 1982-83 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Baltimore Abortion Rights 1981-83 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Brooklyn Anti-Nuclear Group (BANG)
    - Correspondence and actions 1981-82, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Notes May 1981-Winter 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Barnard Abortion and Reproductive Rights Network 1982-83, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bay Area Pro-Choice Coalition Apr 1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bloomington Alliance for Reproductive Choice (BARC) 1981-82 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Boston Women's Health Book Collective
    - Correspondence 1982-83 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Packet 27, Oct 1980 - Jan 1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bread and Roses Women's Health Center 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Chelsea Women's Health Team (New York City) 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Chicago Women's Health Center 1981, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Chicago Women's Health Task Force 1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Choices (New York City) 1979-83 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Cleveland Pro-Choice Action Committee (PCAC) 1981-83, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Committee for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA)
    - Chapters
      - Buffalo 1979-81, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Long Island 1981-83, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Los Angeles 1980-82, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - New Jersey 1980-82, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - New York CARASA
        - General 1978-82, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence with R2N2 1980-82, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - Newsletters Jul 1980-22 May 1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - CARASA News Nov 1980 - Dec 1981 [incomplete] (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - Flyers and pamphlets 1980-83, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - Speeches and drafts 1980-83, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
        - Internal governance
          - General 1979-81, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
          - Steering Committee minutes 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 10)
          - Lesbian controversy 1980, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - Conference 7 June 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - Women's Rights in the Workplace and the Home project Sep 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Coalition to Fight Infant Mortality
    - General 1980-83 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Newsletter Apr 1980-Feb 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Coalition for the Medical Rights of Women (CMRW)
    - General 1980-83, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Second Opinion Jan 1981 - Dec 1984 [incomplete] (Box 3, Folder 17-19)
  - Coalition for Reproductive Choice (Park, MD) 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Coalition for Reproductive Freedom (Jamaica Plain, MA) 1981-83, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Committee to Defend Reproductive Rights (CDRR)
    - General 1980-84, undated (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Sterilization June 10, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Organizing manual 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - CDRR News May 1981 - Jul 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
  - Committee for Equal Rights and Reproductive Freedom 1981-84, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Committee to End Sterilization Abuse (CESA) 1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Democratic Socialists of America/New American Movement (NAM) 1978-82, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Detroit Reproductive Rights Committee 1982-83 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Eastern Women's Center (NYC) 1981-83 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Education for Freedom of Choice in Ohio 1982-83 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Emma Goldman Clinic for Women (Iowa City, IA) 1980-84, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Emma Goldman Health Clinic (Chicago, IL) 1980-83 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Eugene Health Care Coalition (Oregon) 1980-81 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Federation of Feminist Women's Health Centers 1980-85, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Feminist Healthworks (NYC) 1980-81, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Gainesville Women's Health Center (Florida) 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Health Policy Advisory Center 1980 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Health Right, Inc. (NYC) 1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - The Holistic Health Center (Montpelier, VT) 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - International Socialist Organization (ISO) 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - International Socialists (Detroit) 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Iowa Reproductive Rights Coalition (Iowa City) 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Isis Western Massachusetts 1980-82, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Kent Women's Organization (Kent State University) 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Lesbian Activists at Barnard 1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Madison Reproductive Rights Coalition (Wisconsin) 1980-83 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - March for Women's Rights Committee (San Francisco) 1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Massachusetts Childbearing Rights Alliance (MCRA) 1980-82, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Massachusetts Coalition for Reproductive Rights, Berkshire Chapter 1980-82 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Memphis Center for Reproductive Health undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Milwaukee Reproductive Rights Coalition 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Milwaukee Workers Educational Group undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Mobilization for Survival
    - Correspondence with R2N2 1980-83 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Minutes and agendas 1981-82 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Mailings 1981-85, undated (Box 5, Folder 5-9)
    - Pamphlets undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Peacemaking & the Community of Faith" mailing Feb 1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Campaign for Peace with Justice in Central America: organizer's packet 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - New York Mobilizer Summer 1981-Winter 1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper clippings 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - National Committee to Combat Women's Oppression (NCCWO)
    - General 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - NCCWO Bulletin Mar 1981-Mar 1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - National Lawyers Guild 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - New Bedford Women's Center 1984, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - New Hampshire Feminist Health Center (Concord) 1980-82, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - New Haven Feminist Union Reproductive Freedom Task Force
    - General 1981-82, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Press conference packet 22 Jan 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - New Jewish Agenda undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Nia's Task Force for Political Action 1983 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Oberlin Pro-Choice 1981-82 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Olympia Women's Center for Health 1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Orange County (CA) Reproductive Rights Alliance 1980-81 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - People of Washington County (WI) United for Choice 1981-83, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Philadelphia Reproductive Rights Organization/Coalition
    - General
      - 1980-84 (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
      - undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Reproductive Rights: Newsletter of the Philadelphia Reproductive Rights Coalition 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Portland Women's Health Center (Oregon) 1981-84, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Preterm Foundation (Sydney, Australia) 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Progressive Students Network 1980-84, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Reproductive Rights Alliance, Johns Hopkins University 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Reproductive Rights National Network Washington Area Chapter (DC) 1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Revolutionary Workers Headquarters 1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - St. Louis Women's Rights Action Group 1980-83, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Santa Fe Health Education Project 1980-84, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Seacoast Socialist/Feminist Committee 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Seattle Reproductive Rights Alliance 1981-84, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Socialist Party U.S.A. 1980-84, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Sojourner Truth Organization (Chicago): Urgent Tasks No. 11-13 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Solidarity: A Socialist-Feminist Network
    - General 1981-83 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Discussion Bulletin 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - South Coast Committee for Reproductive Rights (California) 1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Southern Students Activist Network 1981 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Terra: Women for Continuing Life on Earth (Denver, CO) 1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Toledo Women Working 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Twin Cities Reproductive Rights Committee 1981-84, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Ulster County Coalition for Reproductive Rights (NY) 1981-83 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Union WAGE (Women's Alliance to Gain Equality)
    - General 1981-83 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Union W.A.G.E.: A Working Woman's Newspaper 1981 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Wimmin for Womyn (New York City) 1982-84, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Women for Reproductive Freedom (Seattle, WA) 1984, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Women's Reproductive Rights Information Centre (London) 1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Women's Health Services (Santa Fe, NM) 1982-83 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Women's Way (Philadelphia) 1985 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Women Organized for Reproductive Choice (WORC)
    - General 1980-81, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Flyers and press releases 1981-84, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Cook County Hospital 1980-85 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - "The New Right Vs.Women's Rights" 1980 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Literature for New Members 1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Proposals to R2N2 1980-81, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Women Organizing Women (WOW) 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Workers Power 1981-82, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Working Women of Hawaii 1981, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- SERIES III. EVENTS
  - Demonstration for Abortion Rights, Cincinnati 23 Jun 1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 7th Anniversary of Roe v. Wade 22 Jan 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Demonstrations around McRae v. Harris Supreme Court decision 30 May-10 Jul 1980 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Coalition for a People's Alternative in 1980: People's Convention, 8-10 Aug 1980
    - Organizing material 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Mailings Jan 1981-Mar 1983 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
    - Task Force on Sexism 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Women '80 March, 26 Aug 1980 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Women's Pentagon Action 16-17 Nov 1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Stony Point Conference 17-18 Jan 1981 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 8th Anniversary of Roe 22 Jan 1981 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Women's Rights Day in Congress 4 Feb 1981 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 8th National Conference on Feminist Psychology 5-8 Mar 1981 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - March on the Pentagon, People's Anti-War Mobilization against U.S. intervention in El Salvador 3 May 1981 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous actions against U.S. intervention in Central America 1981-84 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Southeastern Abortion Rights Conference 4-6 Sep 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Solidarity Day 19 Sep 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - All-People's Congress/National Day of Resistance 16-18 Oct 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - National Peoples' Congress 17-25 Apr 1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Second Special Session on Disarmament Demonstration 12 Jun 1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Federation for Progress National Conference 30 Jul-1 Aug, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Female Adolescence: Challenging Concepts, Exploring Experiences," Barnard College 3-4 Mar 1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - International Women's Day 1981-83 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous 1981-82, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
- SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES
  - Abortion
    - General 1979-85, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Anti-abortion
      - Mailings, articles, and miscellaneous 1973-82, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - "Progressives" 1979-81, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Clinic harassment, bombings, and response 1981-85, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Court cases
      - Lower courts 1981-82, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Supreme Court 1980-83, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Newspaper clippings
        - General 1980-85, undated (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
        - H.L. v. Matheson 1980-81, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - List of amici briefs in various Supreme Court abortion cases undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Amicus curiae brief: drafts, correspondence 1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Harris v. McRae
        - Decision 1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Rehearing support 1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Amicus brief: Motion to Re-Hear Case 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Press releases, petitions, and pamphlets 1980, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Disability 1979, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Editorials 1970-83 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - International 1980-83 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Legislation
      - Fact sheets and updates 1979-83, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Challenges to insurance coverage 1979-83, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Family Protection Act (S1378, HR 311)
        - General 1981-82, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - Text of bill 1981 (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Newspaper clippings 1981-82 (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - National Committee to Combat Women's Oppression (NCCWO) of the National Lawyers' Guild: packet 1981 (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - National Gay Task Force packet 1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Hatfield Amendment (S 2373) 1982 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Human Life Amendment/Human Life Statute
        - General 1981-82, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Newspaper clippings 1981-82, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - Testimonies 1981, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Mailing 10 Nov 1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Hyde Amendment 1980-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Medicaid abortions 1980-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Parental notification for Abortion/"Squeal Rule"
      - U.S. Department of Health and Human Services regulation 1980-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Nicolosi-Padavan bill (New York state) 1980, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Public health 1975-83 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Surgeon General appointment (C. Everett Koop) 1980-81 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Adoption 1979-83 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Ageism and women 1981-83 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - AIDS 1981-1984 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Battered women 1979-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
  - Birth control
    - General 1975-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Cervical Cap 1980-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Dalkon Shield 1980-83, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Depo-Provera